Where do those scars lie within your chest?
sono kizu wa mune no doko ni arimasu ka?
Can you hear my voice somewhere inside your heart?
kono koe wa kokoro no dokoka de kikoeteimasu ka?
When your scars and mine join together...
sono kizu to kono kizu wo kasaneta nara
When my voice and yours resound together...
kono koe to sono koe wo hibikaseta nara
Our intensity, hot tears, and bashful smiles...
hageshisa atsui namida hazukashisou na hohoemi
I used to think nothing of them, but now,
anna ni mo nanimo nai tte omoeteta watashi kara
So many unstoppable feelings are overflowing!
afuredasu yo konna ni mo tomedo nai kanjou ga ima
You're the one who finds yourself.
kimi ga kimi wo mitsukedasu
You're the one who saves yourself.
kimi ga kimi wo sukuidasu
So much is wrong and everyone breaks into a run.
machigai darake de daremo ga hashiridasu
You're the one who lives your own life,
kimi ga kimi wo ikite yuku
Trembling, hesitating all the while
furue nagara, tomadoi nagara
In a world where you're never truly alone.
hitori kiri janai sekai
But you're the only one of you there is!
dakedo kimi wa tatta ichi nin kimi shika inai
I wonder if I'll get to see the fall next year.
（チセ）
来年は 秋 ちゃんと見られるかな
（双子Ａ）
太陽は早寝の日
星と月は夜更かしの日♪
The sun is the light for the early sleepers.
The moon and stars are light for the night owls.
（双子Ｂ）
夜までに
あらゆる祭りを終わらせて♪
Complete all the rituals by night.
The night of Yule comes!
（双子Ａ･Ｂ）
ユールの夜が来るよ♪
Hey, beloved child of the night.
（双子Ａ）やあ 夜の愛(いと)し仔(ご)
Human child.
（双子Ｂ）人の子
（２人）
ユールの支度は終わりそう？
Do you think you'll be done preparing for Yule?
Yule?
ユール？
We're preparing for Yule soon.
（エリアス）
ユールの支度は これからだ
Elias.
エリアス
（双子Ａ）お寝坊さん！
You sleepy-head, the night
will be here before you know it.
夜は すぐに やって来るよ！
Set the Yule Log ablaze in your hearth...
（双子Ｂ）ユールログを燃やすんだ
Before the Horned God and
his Dark Lady walk the earth.
黒い女神と冥府の鹿が
野を歩く前に
Thank you.
（エリアス）
ありがとう　気をつけて
Take care.
Good morning, Elias.
おはようございます エリアス
Who were they?
あの子たちは？
Yule.
（エリアス）ユール
I call them the Yule twins because they
always come on the day of the winter solstice,
冬至の日に いつも やって来るから
ユールの双子と呼んでいるけど
but I don't really know their names.
本当のことは分からない
We're going to be busy today.
今日は忙しくなるよ
Okay.
はい
You have to tell me if you get tired.
（エリアス）
体がつらかったら 言うんだよ
Okay.
はい
I'll tell you, I promise.
絶対 言いますから…
（ルツ）俺は使い魔 失格だ
I'm a failure of a familiar.
I can't help Chise when she's in trouble.
チセが危ないときも
俺は何にもできずに…
He's been like this ever since that day.
（チセ）
この間から こんな状態です
What's even the point?
（エリアス）ふ〜ん
（ルツ）もうダメだ…
I'm done for.
You understand Chise far better than I do, don't you?
（エリアス）
君は 僕より ずっと
チセのことを
分かってるんだろう
It may be tough for you to say
anything because Chise tends to hide things,
チセは隠すから
君は言いづらいの
かもしれないけど
もっと早く 僕に
教えてくれていいんだ
but you can tell me sooner.
I'll take care of it.
そうしたら 僕が何とかするからさ
（チセ）
居たたまれない…
This is painfully awkward.
She's a bit cold right now.
（ルツ）今 ちょっと体が冷えてる
（エリアス）チセ
Chise.
It's because we just came inside.
外から帰ってきたからですよ？
（エリアス）ハア…
さあ…
All right.
Let's prepare for Yule.
ユールの支度を始めよう
It's so pretty.
きれいだな
Is this "pretty"?
（エリアス）これは きれいなの？
I think it is.
（チセ）私は そう思います
（アエトニキ）アエ
（綿蟲(わたむし)）ピィー
There we go.
（エリアス）これでよし
They say that traditionally,
it's okay to kiss under the mistletoe.
ヤドリギの下では
キスをしてもいいって風習も
あるんだよ
（チセ）へえ…
I see...
Want to try it?
（エリアス）やってみる？
（チセ）え？
He looks like he wants to.
（チセ）
やりたそう…
Um...
（チセ）えっと…
かがんでもらってもいいですか？
Could you crouch for me?
Okay.
And back to you.
（エリアス）お返し
（チセ）どうですか？
How was it?
Hmm...
（エリアス）う〜ん 何だろう…
How to phrase it...
My back? My waist? They feel tingly.
背中かな？ 腰かな？ ムズムズする
どうして？
Why?
Dunno.
（チセ）さあ？
One for you too, Ruth.
ルツもね
All right, let's have dinner.
（エリアス）
じゃあ 夕食にしようか
（チセ）はい
Okay.
（コツン コツン…）
Okay, sir, I'll be sure to deliver this.
（ヘーゼル）じゃあ 旦那様
確かに 預かりましたんで
Sorry it's always so last-minute.
（エリアス）
いつも ギリギリで すまないね
It's no problem at all.
いやあ なんも！
Now's my chance.
（チセ）
今のうち…
It'll be okay, I left a note.
大丈夫 書き置きしてきたし
Bye.
（ヘーゼル）そんじゃ
（チセ）すごい人…
So many people.
（ルツ）チセ 俺は中にいる
Chise, I'll be inside.
Okay.
（アリス）
悪いな ロンドンまで呼んじまって
Sorry to drag you all the way out to London.
So, um...
（チセ）それで えっと…
クリスマスのプレゼントだっけ？
レンフレッドさんの
A Christmas present, right?
For Renfred-san.
Yeah.
You really don't know what to get for him?
本当に 何をあげたらいいのか
分からないの？
What did you get him before?
前は 何を？
（アリス）
前は その… 逆に もらってて
Before, well...
He was the one giving me gifts,
so I thought this year, I'd get him something.
だから 今年はと思って
They're eating.
（客Ａ）食べてる…
They're really digging in.
（客Ｂ）すごい食べてる
（アリス）
お… お前は何か やんないのか？
あの骨頭(ほねあたま)に
Aren't you getting that bonehead anything?
私？
Me?
考えてなかった…
I'd never even thought about it.
（アリス）なら…
Let's go look for a present together, then.
今日は２人で
プレゼント探しだな！
Wait...
（チセ）あ… ちょっと！
（チセ）
“道連れ”って顔してる…
She's not giving me a choice, is she?
Did you find anything good?
（チセ）いいもの あった？
Nope.
ん〜ん… 好みもあるしな
There's the question of taste, too.
What about you?
そっちは？
そもそも 好みが分からないし
I don't even know what his tastes are.
Sorry.
ごめんね
（チセ）
誰かにプレゼントなんて
あげたことなくて
I've never given anyone a gift before.
（アリス）
あたしは その…
知り合いが あんまし いなくて
I don't... well, I don't know too many people.
M-Me, neither.
（チセ）わ… 私も
I don't know anyone like that, either.
（チセ）そういう人 いなくて
（アリス）じゃあさ
We're in the same boat, then.
あたしとチセは仲間だな
In the same boat?
仲間？
You're a mage and I'm a sorcerer,
魔法か魔術か 違いはあるけどさ
but we both live our lives studying with our masters.
お互い師匠について
勉強して生きてる
So we're in the same boat.
だから 仲間
そっか
Oh.
You're right.
そうだね
（ヘーゼル）おや
Hey, it's the lady from Mr. Ainsworth's place.
エインズワースの旦那さん所の
娘さんじゃありませんか
（チセ）あ… ヘーゼルさん どうも
Hazel-san. Hello.
Who are you talking to, Chise?
チセ？ 何と話してんだ？
おんや お連れさんは…
Oh, is your friend...
Unlike mages, sorcerers don't notice
people like us, who've disguised ourselves.
（ヘーゼル）
魔術師は魔法使いと違って
目くらましをかけた
俺たちみてえなのには
気付かねえんでさ
Nice to meet you, my lady.
はじめまして お嬢さん
Christmas presents, huh?
（ヘーゼル）
へ〜 クリスマスプレゼントを
（チセ）そうなんですけど…
Yeah...
（２人）ハア…
What about something that you can picture them using?
その人が使っているところを
想像できるものは どうです？
その人んことを よ〜く思い出して
しっくりくるものを考えるんでさあ
Think really carefully about them.
Imagine something that makes sense.
Want to take another lap around?
もうひと回りするか
だね
Okay.
Something he uses all the time, huh?
（アリス）普段(ふだん)使いしてるものか…
（チセ）ちょっと 思いついたかも
I think I have an idea.
No fair! Tell me.
（アリス）ずりい！ 教えろ！
You can't copy me, though.
（チセ）まねはダメだよ
Hey, it's Alice.
（男Ａ）お？ アリスじゃねえか
Let's go, Chise.
（アリス）行くぞ チセ
What?
（男Ａ）
何だよ 昔みたいに遊ぼうぜ
Let's hang out, like old times.
I'm not doing drugs anymore.
（アリス）薬は もう やんねえ
Yo!
（男Ａ）おい！
You...
（男Ｂ）てっめえ！
（ルツ）ウウウ…
Wh-Where the hell did you...
どっ どこから…
Go!
（アリス）行くぞ！
（チセ）うん
（アリス･チセ）ハア… ハア…
Sorry about that.
（アリス）ごめんな
昔の残りカスってやつ
They're just stragglers from my past.
ハア…
アリスさん
Alice-san...
薬って おいしいの？
Do drugs taste good?
アハッ！ うまくねえよ
Not at all.
They're not my thing.
あたしには合わない
I didn't start by choice, either.
好きで始めたわけでもねえし
今でも 夢みたいでさ
It's still like a dream.
（アリス）
あ〜 こんな話 面白くねえな
やめやめ…
This isn't fun to talk about.
Let's not.
（チセ）いいよ
It's okay.
聞きたい
I want to hear.
My shitty parents got me into drugs.
（アリス）師匠(せんせい)は…
クソ親に薬 仕込まれて
I had nothing going for me outside of
selling that crap, when Master took me in.
売人やるしか生きる道がなかった
あたしを
拾ってくれたんだ
Hey, have you seen the blonde brat?
（男Ｃ）
おい 金髪のガキ 見てねえか？
We need to teach her a lesson.
（男Ｄ）
きっちり しつけてやんねえと
What the hell are you looking at?
（幼いアリス）なに見てやがる
何すっ…
What are you...
Do you want to stay here forever?
（レンフレッド）
お前… このまま ずっと
ここにいたいか？
嫌だ！
No!
I haven't introduced myself yet.
（レンフレッド）
自己紹介が まだだったな
I'm Mikhail Renfred.
私はミハイル･レンフレッド
Call me what you want.
まあ 好きに呼べ
おい てめえ！
Hey, asshole...
（レンフレッド）風呂が先だ
Take a bath first.
Wait...
（幼いアリス）ハア… ハア…
I didn't trust him in the slightest at the time.
（アリス）
あのころは まだ
師匠のこと 全然 信用してなくて
Before that, I'd grown up in a trash pit.
それまで ごみ溜(だ)めみたいなとこで
生きてきた あたしには
There was no way I could trust people.
人を信じるなんて 無理な話でさ
But, one day...
だけど あのとき…
What a pain.
（幼いアリス）めんどくせえ
I can't read the title.
タイトル 読めねえ
I told you not to open them!
（レンフレッド）
中は開(ひら)くなと言っただろう！
Ow!
（幼いアリス）ってえな！
（レンフレッド）いや…
No, that was my fault, too.
私も悪かった
きちんと指示すればよかったな
I should have told you more clearly.
Why?
どうして？
Your face...
（アリス）けが！
（レンフレッド）ん？
You're hurt.
（アリス）顔が…
It's fine.
ああ かまわない
ハア…
でも よかった
I'm glad, though.
せっかく元気になったのに
傷なんて 作るものじゃない
You're finally getting better.
You shouldn't be getting yourself hurt again.
This way.
（幼いアリス）こっち
I'm used to treating wounds.
（幼いアリス）
手当てなら 慣れてっから
ちゃんとできる
I can do it.
I'm self-taught, though.
自己流だけど
I'm sorry.
ごめん
I'll be more careful.
次は ちゃんとする…
I'll protect you, as your bodyguard.
護(まも)り手として あんたのこと 護る
I'm counting on you next time.
（レンフレッド）次は 頼んだぞ
Thinking about that makes me feel like shit.
思い出したら しんどくなってきた
（チセ）ごめんなさい
（アリス）ん？
I'm sorry.
I don't know what to say.
何て言ったらいいか 分からなくて
You don't need to think anything about it.
（アリス）
チセが どうこう考える必要ねえよ
I'll decide for myself whether I'm happy or miserable.
てめえが幸せか不幸かなんて
てめえで決めるさ
Thanks for hearing me out.
聞いてくれて ありがとな
よし！ 戻るぞ
All right, let's get back.
Yeah.
Oh yeah, is my servant bird at your place?
（アリス）
そういえば お前たちのとこ
使い鳥が行ってないか？
It's this tiny thing.
小さいやつ
Oh, never mind.
（アリス）ああ… いや 何でもない
I'll write you a letter again.
じゃあ また 手紙 書くよ
Thanks for coming out at the last minute.
ギリギリまで ありがとうな
No, thank you, too.
ううん　私も ありがとう
お互い うまくいくといいな！
I hope it works out for both of us.
You have a friend now. I'm happy for you.
（ルツ）よかったな 仲間が出来て
As my big brother, do you approve?
（チセ）お兄さんから見て 合格？
She's not a bad person.
（ルツ）悪いヤツじゃないな
（イーサン）アハハハ！
（ステラ）ちょっと イーサン！
Jeez, Ethan!
I'm sorry!
ごめんなさ〜い！
（母親）ステラ！ イーサン！
Stella! Ethan!
Let's head home, then.
じゃあ 帰ろうか
（エリアス）おかえり チセ
Welcome home, Chise.
遅かったね
You're late.
Thanks, Elias.
（チセ）ただいま… エリアス
（ドアが閉まる音）
（エリアス）
ロンドンまで
何が欲しくて行ってきたんだ？
What did you want all the way out in London?
And you even met with Renfred's apprentice.
レンフレッドの弟子とも会って
Y-You were watching?
み… 見てたんですか？
（エリアス）だって 君
Do you know how many
times you've put yourself in danger?
何度 危ない目に遭ってると
思ってるの
You can't sneak out like that.
黙って行くなんて
I thought you'd say no.
（チセ）
ダメって言われると
思って…
Of course I would.
（エリアス）
言うよ それは
I was with her.
（ルツ）俺がいた
Don't be too angry, Elias.
あまり怒るな エリアス
Angry?
（エリアス）怒る？
怒ってるの？ 僕は
This is angry? I am?
（チセ）多分…
I think so.
ごめんなさい
I'm sorry.
えっと これを買いに…
Um...
I went to buy this.
I know it's a day early, but...
その… まだ１日 早いですけど
メリークリスマス
Merry Christmas.
Elias?
エリアス？
Oh, right.
（エリアス）あ… そうか
I didn't think you'd get me anything.
くれるとは思わなかった
I didn't think I'd get you anything.
（チセ）
あげようと思ってなかった…
ごめんなさい エリアス
I'm sorry, Elias.
（チセ）えっと…
Uh...
You're always wearing the same one,
so I thought maybe it relaxes you.
いつも同じものをつけてるから
落ち着くのかと思って
I-If you don't like it...
きっ 気に入らなかったら…
（アエトニキ）アエ？
（エリアス）ありがとう チセ
Thanks, Chise.
One for you, too, then.
じゃあ チセにも
It's big.
（チセ）おっきい…
I've only made them for Angelica and her family.
（エリアス）
アンジェリカたちにしか
作ったことなかったんだけど
チセにもと思って
I thought I'd make one for you, too.
（チセ）
作ったんですか？ エリアスが？
You made this?
You did?
Yeah.
Angelica told me a long time ago
that she wanted a teddy bear as a gift.
昔 アンジェリカに言われたんだ
プレゼントに
クマのぬいぐるみが欲しいって
I think this year's is my best one yet.
多分 今年作った それが
いちばんうまく出来てる
You've been doing it ever since?
（チセ）
もしかして それから ずっと…
Yeah.
I don't really know what else to do.
ほかのものは
よく分からなくて
Thank you.
（チセ）
ありがとうございます
It has a bit of a trick, too.
（エリアス）
ちょっとした仕掛けもあるよ
Also...
あと…
Those are all gifts for you.
あれも みんな 君へのプレゼント
Angelica, Simon, and Lindel have gotten you gifts, too.
アンジェリカやサイモン
リンデルからも届いてる
Gifts are meant to be opened on Christmas Day,
（エリアス）
本当なら
贈り物は当日に開けるものだから
so these are for tomorrow.
これは 明日ね
はい
Okay.
（エリアス）
ほら 先に夕食にしよう
All right, let's have dinner first.
お説教は あとでね
I'll scold you after.
（チセ）
う… 忘れてくれてなかった
I was hoping he'd forgotten.
（エリアス）
言ってくれたら ついていったし
You should have told me. I would have gone with you.
いろいろ買い物もできたのに
And I could have gotten some shopping done.
I wouldn't agree to that.
（チセ）それは ちょっと…
I had a secret talk with another girl about girl stuff.
女の子同士の秘密の話があったので
Is this what Christmas is supposed to be like?
（チセ）
クリスマスって
こんな感じ… だったっけ
（チセ）
次の日が楽しみになるなんて
I can't believe I'm looking forward to waking up.
信じられない
Oh?
（灰の目）おや
I see a pitiful child.
哀れな子がおるなあ
The moon witnessed our incomplete cycles.
tsuki wa miteita kaketeru bokura
We called to one another,
tagai wo yobiai nagara
Walking distant paths as we took the long way around.
toomawari de tooi michi wo aruita
Red and black attract one another...
hikiyoseau aka to kuro ga
Shadow and light chase after one another...
oikakeau yami to hikari ga
They're made of two related things
futatsu no tsuranaru mono de tsukurareteru yo
...everything in this world is.
konoyo no subete wa
Because you're here, I'm here.
anata ga iru kara watashi wa iru
Even apart, we're side by side.
hanaretemo soba ni iru
soba ni iru
We're side by side.
Everyone is continually searching
daremo ga jibun no mou hitotsu no
For one precious thing
kataware to iu taisetsu na mono
That they can call their other half.
sagashi tsudzuketeru yo
An ancient being, Ashen Eye.
（チセ）
古きもの 灰の目
Siblings that are at the mercy of his eternal life.
悠久の時を生きる彼に
翻弄される姉弟(きょうだい)
The mage and the girl lend them a hand, but...
魔法使いと少女は
姉弟たちのために手を貸すが…
（ステラ）返して！ 私の弟よ
Give him back! He's my brother!